21 BEN weather staff One of the strange things about living in the world is that
it is only now and then one is quite sure one is going to live forever and
ever and ever. One knows it sometimes when one gets up at the tender solemn
Dawn time and goes out and stands alone and throws one's head far back and looks
up and up and watches the pale sky slowly changing and flushing and
marvelous unknown things happening until the East almost makes one cry out and
one's heart stands still at the strange unchanging majesty of the rising of the
sun— —which has been happening every morning for thousands and thousands
thousand and thousands of years. One knows it then for a moment or
so. And one knows it sometimes when one stands by oneself in a wood at sunset
and the mysterious deep gold stillness slanting through and under the branches
seems to be saying slowly again and again something one cannot quite hear, however much one
tries. Then sometimes the immense quiet of the dark blue at night with millions
of stars waiting and watching makes one sure; and sometimes a sound of far off
music makes it true; and sometimes a look in someone's eyes. And it was like that with Colin
when he first saw and heard and felt the Springtime inside the four high walls of a hidden
garden. That afternoon the whole world seemed to devote itself to being perfect
and radiantly beautiful and kind to to one boy. Perhaps out of pure heavenly
goodness the spring came and crowded everything it possibly could into that one
place. More than once Dickon paused in what he was doing and stood still with a
sort of growing wonder in his eyes, shaking his head
softly he it is gradely he said. "I'm 12 going on 13 and there's a lot of
afternoons in 13 years, but seems to me like I never seed one as gradely as this
ear ah it is a gradely one," said Mary, and she sighed for mere joy. "I'll warrant
it's the grest one as ever was in this world." "Does that think," said Colin with
dreamy carefulness, "as happen it was made like this ear all a purpose for
me?" "My word!" cried Mary admiringly, "that there is a bit of good
Yorkshire thought shaping First Rate that thou art." And delight rained They drew the
chair under the Plum Tree which was Snow White with blossoms and musical with
bees. It was like a king's canopy, a fairy king's. There were flowering cherry trees
near and apple trees whose buds were pink and white, and here and there one had burst open
wide. Between the blossoming branches of the canopy bits of blue sky looked down like wonderful
eyes. Mary and Dickon worked a little here and there and Colin watched them.
They brought him things to look at— —buds which were opening, buds which were tight
closed, bits of twig whose leaves were just showing green, the feather of a
woodpecker which had dropped on the grass, the empty shell of some bird early
hatched. Dickon pushed pushed the chair slowly round and round the garden,
stopping every other moment to let him look at wonders springing out of the
earth or trailing down from trees. It was like being taken in state
around the country of a magic king and queen and shown all the mysterious riches it
contained. "I wonder if we shall see the robin?" said Colin they'll see him often now after a
bit," answered Dickon. "When they eggs hatches out the little chap he'll be
kept so busy it'll make his head swim they'll see him flying backward and
forward carrying worms nigh as big as himself and that much noise going on in
the nest when he gets there as fair flusters him so as he scarce knows which
big mouth to drop the first piece in and gaping beaks and squarks on every side.
Mother says as when she sees the worker robin has to keep them aping beaks
filled, she feels like she was a lady with nothing to do. She says she's seen
the little chaps when it seemed like the sweat must be dropping off them though folk can't see
it." This made them giggle so delightedly that they were obliged to cover their
mouths with their hands, remembering that they must not be
heard. Colin had been instructed as to the lore of whispers and low voices several days before.
He liked the mysteriousness of it and did his best, but in the midst of excited
enjoyment it is rather difficult never to laugh above a whisper. Every moment of the afternoon
was full of new things and every hour the sunshine grew more
golden. The wheeled chair had been drawn back under the canopy and Dickon had sat
down on the grass and had just drawn out his pipe when Colin saw something he had
not had time to notice before. "That's a very old tree over there,
isn't it?" he said dick looked across the grass at the tree and Mary looked and
there was a brief moment of stillness. "Yes," answered Dicken after it,
and his low voice had a very gentle sound. Mary gazed at the tree and
thought. "The branches are quite gray and there's not a single leaf anywhere," Colin went on.
"It's quite dead, isn't it I admitted Dickon. "But them roses as
has climbed all over it will near hide every bit of the dead wood when they're
full of leaves and flowers. It won't look dead then. It'll be the prettiest of
all." Mary still gazed at the tree and thought. "It looks as if a big branch had
been broken off," said Colin. "I wonder how it was done." "It's been done many a year
here answered Dickon he with a sudden relieved start and laying his hand on
Colin. "Look at that robin! There he is!
He's been foraging for his mate." Colin was almost too late but he just caught
sight of him, the flash of red breasted bird with something in his beak. He
darted through the greenness and into the close grown corner and was out of
sight. Colin leaned back on his cushion again, laughing a little. "He's taking her
tea to her. Perhaps it's 5:00 I think I'd like some tea myself." And so they were
safe. "It was Magic which sent the robin," said Mary secretly to Dickon
afterward. "I know it was Magic." For both she and Dickon had been
afraid Colin might ask something about the tree whose branch had broken off 10
years ago and they had talked it over together and Dickon had stood and rubbed
his head in a troubled way wean looked as if it wasn't no different from the
other trees," he had said. "We couldn't never tell him how it broke, poor lad. If
he says anything about it we must wean try to look cheerful I that wean had answered Mary.
But she had not felt as if she looked cheerful when she gazed at the
tree. She wondered and wondered in those few moments if there was any reality in
that other thing dickan had said. He had gone on rubbing his rust red hair in a
puzzled way, but a nice comforted look had begun to grow in his blue
eyes. "Mrs. Craven was a very lovely young lady," he had gone on rather
hesitatingly and mother she thinks maybe she's about mwe many a time looking
after Mr Colin, same as all mothers do when they're took out of the world. They
have to come back theis Happen she's been in the garden
and and it was her set us to work and told us to bring him
here." Mary had thought he meant something about Magic. She was a great believer in
Magic. Secretly she quite believed that Dickon worked Magic, of course good Magic,
on everything near him and that was why people liked him so much and wild
creatures knew he was their friend. She wondered, indeed, if it were not possible
that his gift had brought the robin just at the right moment when Colin asked
that dangerous question. She felt that his Magic was working all the afternoon
and making Colin look like an entirely different boy. It did not seem possible
that he could be the crazy creature who had screamed and beaten and bitten his
pillow. Even his ivory whiteness seemed to change. The faint glow of color which had
Shone on his face and neck and hands when he first got inside the garden
really never quite died away. He looked as if he were made of flesh instead of ivory or
wax. They saw the robin carry food to his mate two or three times, and it was so
suggestive of afternoon tea that Colin felt they must have some. "Go and make one
of the men's servants bring some in a basket to the rad ofender and walk," he
said. "And then you and Dickon can bring it here." It was an agreeable IDE idea,
easily carried out, and when the white cloth was spread upon the grass, with hot
tea and buttered toast and crumpets, a delightfully hungry meal was eaten, and
several birds on domestic errands paused to inquire what was going on and were
led into investigating crumbs with great activity. Nut and Shell whisked up trees
with pieces of cake and suot took the entire half of a buttered crumpet into a
corner and pecked at and examined and turned it over and made horar remarks
about it until he decided to swallow it all joyfully in one
gulp. The afternoon was dragging toward its mellow hour. The sun was deepening
the gold of its lances, the bees were going home and the birds were flying past less
often. Dickon and Mary were sitting on the grass, the tea basket was repacked
ready to be taken back to the house, and Colin was lying against his cushions
with his heavy locks pushed back from his forehead and his face looking quite
a natural color. "I don't want this afternoon to go," he said; "but I shall come
back tomorrow and the day after, and the day after, and the day
after." "You'll get plenty of fresh air, won't you?" said Mary. "I'm going to get
nothing else," he answered. "I've seen the spring now and I'm going to see the
summer. I'm going to see everything grow here. I'm going to grow here myself." "That
thou will," said Dickon us will have thee walking about here and digging same as
other folk afor long." Colin flushed tremendously. "Walk!" he said. "Dig! Shall I
dickens's glance at him was delicately cautious. Neither he nor Mary had ever
asked if anything was the matter with his legs. "For sure thou will," he said stoutly
there thk got legs of thine own, same as other folks!" Mary was rather frightened until
she heard Colin's answer. "Nothing really ales them," he said,
"but they are so thin and weak. They shake so that I'm afraid to try to stand on
them." Both Mary and Dickon drew a relieved breath. "When thou stops being afraid th
stand on them Dickon said with renewed cheer and th stop being afraid in a bit." "I shall?"
said Colin, and he lay still as if he were wondering about
things. They were really very quiet for a little while. The sun was dropping lower.
It was that hour when everything stills itself, and they really had had a busy and exciting
afternoon. Colin looked as if he were resting luxuriously. Even the creatures had
ceased moving about and had drawn together and were resting near them
suot had perched on a low branch and drawn up one leg and dropped the gray
film drowsily over his eyes. Mary privately thought he looked as if he might snore in a
minute. In the midst of this stillness it was rather startling when Colin half
lifted his head and exclaimed in a loud suddenly alarmed whisper: "Who is that man?"
Dickon and Mary scrambled to their feet.
"Man!" they both cried in low quick voices.
Colin pointed to the high wall. "Look!" he whispered excitedly. "Just look!" Mary and
Dickon wheeled about and looked. There was Ben weather staff's indignant face
glaring at them over the wall from the top of a ladder! He actually shook his fist at
Mary. "If I wasn't a bacheler and that was
a wench of mine," he cried, "I'd give thee a hiding He mounted another step
threateningly as if it were his energetic intention to jump down and
deal with her; but as she came toward him he evidently thought better of it and
stood on the top step of his ladder shaking his fist down at her. "I never
thought much of thee!" he hared I could not abide thee the first time I set eyes
on thee. A scrawny buttermilk young beum all us asking questions and poke in thy
nose where it wasn't not wanted. I never know how thou got so thick with me. If it
hadn't been for the robin— —Drat him—" "Ben weather stuff called out Mary, finding
her breath. She stood below him and called up to him with a sort of gasp. "Ben
weather stuff it was the robin who showed me the
way!" Then it did seem as if Ben really would scramble down on her side of the
wall, he was so outraged th young badon he called down at her
laying that badness on a robin,— ,—not but what he's impid to now for anything Him
showing thee the way! Him hey th young n she could see his next words burst out
because he was overpowered by curiosity how however i' this world did
thou get in?" "It was the robin who showed me the way," she protested
obstinately. "He didn't know he was doing it but he did. And I can't tell you from
here while you're shaking your fist at me." He stopped shaking his fist very
suddenly at that very moment and his jaw actually dropped as he stared over her
head at something he saw coming over the grass toward him. At the first sound of
his torrent of words Colin had been so surprised that he had only sat up and
listened as if he were spellbound. But in the midst of it he had recovered himself and beckoned
imperiously to Dickon. "Wheel me over there!" he commanded.
"Wheel me quite close and stop right in front of
him!" And this, if you please, this is what Ben weather staff beheld and which made his jaw
drop. A wheelchair with luxurious cushions and robes which came toward him
looking rather like some sort of State Coach because a young rajer leaned back
in it with royal command in his great black rimmed eyes and a thin white hand
extended haughtily toward him. And it stopped right under Ben weather staff's
nose. It was really no wonder his mouth dropped open. "Do you know who I am?"
demanded the Raja How Ben weather staff stared! His red old eyes fixed themselves on what
was before him as if he were seeing a ghost. He gazed and gazed and gulped a
lump down his throat and did not say a word. "Do you know know who I am?" demanded
Colin still more imperiously.
"Answer!" Ben Weatherstaff put his gnarled hand up and passed it over his eyes and
over his forehead and then he did answer in a queer shaky
voice. "Who Thou art?" he said I that I do with our mother's eyes staring at me out
of th face. Lord knows how Thou come here.
But th the poor Colin forgot that he had ever had a back. His face flushed scarlet and
he sat bolt upright. "I'm not a he cried out furiously. "I'm not!" "He's not!"
cried Mary, almost shouting up the wall in her fierce indignation. "He's not got a
lump as big as a pin! I looked and there was none there— —not one!" Ben weather staff
passed his hand over his forehead again and gazed as if he could never gaze
enough. His hand shook and his mouth shook and his voice shook. He was
ignorant old man and a tactless old man and he could only remember the things he had
heard that that hasn't got a crooked back?" he said hoarsely. "No!" shouted Colin that that
hasn't got crooked legs?" quavered Ben more hely yet. It was too much. The
strength which Colin usually threw into his tantrums rushed through him now in a
new way. Never yet had he been accused of crooked legs— —even in whispers— —and the
perfectly simple belief in their existence which was revealed by Ben
Weatherstaff's voice was more than Raja flesh and blood could
endure. His anger and insulted pride made him forget everything but this one
moment and filled him with a power he had never known before, an almost
unnatural strength. "Come here!" he shouted to Dickon, and he actually began to tear
the coverings off his lower limbs and disentangle himself. "Come here! Come here! This minute!"
Dickon was by his side in a second. Mary caught her breath in a short gasp and
felt herself turn pale. "He can do it! He
can do it! He can do it! He can!" she gabbled over to herself under her breath
as fast as ever she could. There was a brief fierce scramble,
the rugs were tossed onto the ground, Dickon held Colin's arm, the thin legs
were out, the thin feet were on the grass.
Colin was standing upright— —upright— —as straight as an arrow and looking
strangely tall— —his head thrown back and his strange eyes flashing
lightning. "Look at me!" he flung up at Ben weather staff Just look at me— —you! Just
look at me!" "He's as straight as I am!"
cried Dickon. "He's as straight as any lad on Yorkshire!" What Ben weather staff did
Mary thought queer beyond measure. He choked and gulped and suddenly tears ran
down his weather wrinkled cheeks as he struck his old hands together. "Eh!" he
burst forth the lies folk tells thou as thin as a lath and as white as a wraith,
but there's not a knob on thee thou make a man yet. God bless thee!" Dickon held
Colin's arm strongly but the boy had not begun to falter. He stood straighter and
straighter and looked Ben Weatherstaff in the face. "I'm your master," he said, "when my
father is away. And you are to obey me.
This is my garden. Don't dare to say a word about it! You get down from that
ladder and go out to the Long Walk and Miss Mary will meet you and bring you
here. I want to talk to you. We did not
want you, but now you will have to be in the secret. Be
quick!" Ben weather staff's crabbed old face was still wet with that one queer
rush of tears. It seemed as if he could not take his eyes from thin straight
Collins standing on his feet with his head thrown back he lad," he almost whispered a my
lad!" And then remembering himself he suddenly touched his hat gardener fashion and
said, "Yes, sir! Yes, sir!" and obediently disappeared as he descended the ladder